They don't need a reason.
The Strangers: Chapter 1 is a horror, thriller film directed by Renny Harlin.
After their car breaks down in an eerie small town, a young couple
are forced to spend the night in a remote cabin.
Panic ensues as they are terrorized by three masked strangers who
strike with no mercy and seemingly no motives.
Maya, played by Madelaine Petsch.
Ryan, played by Froy Gutierrez.
Gregory, played by Gabriel Basso.
Shelly, played by Ema Horvath.
Jasmine, played by Ella Bruccoleri.
Sheriff Rotter, played by Richard Brake.
The Strangers: Chapter 1 is a 2024 American horror film.
It is the third film in The Strangers film series and the first installment
of an intended relaunch in the form of a standalone trilogy.
It was directed by Renny Harlin, with a screenplay by Alan R.
Cohen and Alan Freedland, from a story by Bryan Bertino, the
writer and director of the original film.
The film stars Madelaine Petsch, Froy Gutierrez and Ema Horvath, and follows a couple who come
into contact with three psychopathic masked strangers while on a road trip.
Plans for a consecutively shot trilogy of Strangers films were announced
in August 2022 by the original film's producer, Roy Lee.
Harlin was announced as the director of all three the following
month, with most of the cast joining soon after.
Production on the films took place in Bratislava between September and November that year,
often alternating daily between which of the three Chapters was being shot.
The Strangers: Chapter 1 had its world premiere at Regal L.A.
Live on May 8, 2024, and was released theatrically in the
United States by Lionsgate Films on May 17, 2024.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics
and grossed over $48.2 million worldwide.
The film's sequel, The Strangers – Chapter 2, was released on September 26,
2025, and Chapter 3 is expected to be released on February 6, 2026.
The film explores themes of mask, remake, murder, slasher, home invasion.
The tone is dark and intense.